Bjørn Mathisen

224-622-8543 || thebcm27@gmail.com

Automation Engineer and Software Developer | Minneapolis, Minnesota

Summary

A QA and IT professional with a Bachelors in Computer Science and two years' experience in Software Quality Assurance with expertise in Automation Testing, Manual UI Testing, Web API Testing and Technical Writing. In addition, two more years of experience as a Software Developer handling frontend product integration using C# ASP.Net, and experience as a freelance web designer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

.Net: C#, C++, ASP.Net, .Net Core, MVC, MVVM Web: JavaScript, XML, WPF, TypeScript

Database: MS SQL, Mongo DB **Automation**: Selenium, C.A.T.S., Postman, Cypress, Cucumber

Tools: Jira, Trello, Azure DevOps IDEs: Visual Studio, Rider, VS Code, Eclipse

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cognizant Softvision: Minneapolis, MN

July 2021 - Present (1 year 8 months) | Automation Engineer and Quality Assurance Engineer While working at Cognizant Softvision I have been assigned numerous clients to help them deliver their product goals on time and in a variety of Agile work environments. I have been responsible for writing automated tests using a many different languages and frameworks from Selenium, MAQS, C.A.T.S and PlayWright, and in my own time developed a working knowledge of the Cypress and Cucumber frameworks.

TriZetto Provider Solutions: Minneapolis, MN

July 2022 - Present | **Automation Engineer**

While currently working at TriZetto I am responsible for automation test case creation, execution, and reporting for their frontend software. These responsibilities require testing various API calls through Postman and UI elements through Selenium C# and the C.A.T.S Frameworks all while using the P.O.M programming design pattern.

Trane Technologies: Minneapolis, MN

July 2021 – Jun 2022 | Quality & Automation Engineer

While working at Trane Technologies I was responsible for manual and automated test case creation and execution for their point of sales portal. This required daily testing of various API and UI elements, the creation of bug reports, and analyzing existing workflows for bugs, etc. while maintaining direct and continuous communication with developers and product owners to deliver 100 percent code coverage and a fast turnaround time on all QA tasks.

Andersen Windows: Minneapolis, MN

Jan 2021 – June 2021 - 6 Month Contract | Software Engineer

Worked within a small team using an Agile style workflow to take on requests from Home Depot business contacts to facilitate adding products and making changes to existing products for their front end catalog software. Met daily with QA to ensure code compliances and for quality testing of completed work. Wrote unit tests prior to submitting to QA for quality assurance testing.

Micro Center: Saint Louis Park, MN

Nov 2019 – Jan 2021 | Computer Service Technician

While working as a Computer Service Tech besides repairing computer systems, managing inventory, parts ordering, and customer service issues I wrote bash and python programs to help diagnose troublesome computers networking and windows installation to help repair whatever issues they were facing as well as diagnose the problem.

Martina Carter Entertainment: Chicago, IL

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019 - Freelance | Website Programmer

Worked with the client to design and build a custom website for their product presentation which was designed to display the client's image heavy product listings, while helping with the booking of clients through a portal.

Zerma | Chicago, IL

Jan 2019 – July 2019 - Freelance | Data Analyst and Python Programmer

Wrote a Python web crawler extract information and format the customer data in XML. Created a SQL database hosted on AWS and wrote SQL queries to join and merge the data while using advanced database techniques to remove 100% of the inaccurate information contrasted against the existing data set, trimming down the data size from 45,000 non usable data points to 17,000 usable data points

EDUCATION AND TRAINING (CERTIFICATIONS)

- Bachelors in Computer Science | Principia College | 2014-2018
 - **Notable Classes: Hardware Architecture** where as a team of 12 we designed, programmed, and constructed a fully functional 32bit micro controlled computer, capable of doing basic arithmetic and string manipulation.
- Toastmasters Competent Communicator | Gavel Club | 2014
- **Eagle Scout** "Eagle Scout" is not just an award; it is a state of being. It represents integrity and the ability to do hard work

LANGUAGES

• Language | English | Fluent